Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（リコ）ねぇ 日向(ひゅうが)君
夏休みは 海が いいかなー？
Say, Hyuga,
should we go to the beach during summer vacation?
Yeah, the beach is nice.
（日向）あー 海も いいなー
Or maybe the mountains?
（リコ）それとも 山かなー？
Yeah, mountains are good too.
（日向）あー 山も いいなー
Hey, are you even listening?
ちょっとー ちゃんと聞いてる？
んー？
つーか… いーよ どこでも
Hm? I don't care where we go,
as long as we can practice hard.
合宿なんて シゴければ
Don't decide on the hell we're going to like a couple!
（２年生たち）地獄の行き先
カップルみてーに決めんな！
（木吉(きよし)）ん？
Episode 21
Let's Get Started
（リコ）今年は
夏休みの始めと終わり—
This year, at the beginning and end of summer vacation, we'll be taking a trip to the beach and then to the mountains!
海と山で 合宿 ２回よ！
They chose both!
（２年生たち）両方 きちゃった！
The qualifiers for the Winter Cup start shortly after summer vacation ends!
（日向）夏休み明けたら—
ウインターカップ予選は
すぐそこだ！
It's important we use this vacation as effectively as possible.
この休みを どこまで
有効に使えるかが大事だ
Let's give it everything we have!
気合入れて行くぞ！
以上 解散！
That's all. Dismissed!
Good work!
（一同）お疲れしたぁ！
ごめん 合宿の件で
先生と話さなきゃいけないから—
Sorry. I have to go talk to the teachers about our training camps.
先 あがるね
Okay.
おう
（火神(かがみ)）いてっ
Ow.
Sorry.
（黒子(くろこ)）すみません
That hurt. Look where you're walking!
（火神）
痛(いて)えな ちゃんと 前 見ろよ！
Kagami, please don't stagger around like that.
火神君も
フラフラしないでください
It's his fault for hanging around my feet.
こいつが足元ちょろちょろすっから
いけねーんだよ
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）わん！
Hey, get away from me!
コラ ひっつくな！
It seems we'll be able to take Number 2 with us on our trips.
合宿には
２号も連れていきます
The guesthouse will allow it.
民宿の人が
許してくれたそうです
Don't bring him! He's annoying!
んなもん連れてくな！ うぜぇ！
（テツヤ２号）わん！
Kagami, you're so mean.
（黒子）火神君 ひどいです
（テツヤ２号）わん！ わん！
（火神）だぁ！ 離れろっ！
Get away from me!
They've started talking to each other again, but they seem to be arguing a lot more.
（小金井(こがねい)）なんか 最近
また口きくようになったけど—
前より ケンカ 増えてね？
Are they okay?
（土田(つちだ)）大丈夫か？ あいつら
They're fine.
（木吉）大丈夫だって
But they didn't pass to each other during practice today.
けど 今日の練習も
全然 パスとかなかったけど
That's just for now.
まぁ 今だけだって
冬には また やってくれるさ
They'll play together again in the winter.
全員！ もっかい 集合！
One more time, everyone! Gather 'round!
We're currently facing grave danger.
オレたちは 今…
重大な危機に直面している
今年は 合宿を２回やるために
宿は 格安の民宿にした
In order to make two trips this year, we chose cheap lodgings.
We'll have to make our own food, which is where our problem lies.
よって 食事は自炊だ
が 問題は ここからだ
カントクが…
メシを作る！
The coach will be...
cooking for us!
（降旗(ふりはた)）え？
ダメ… なんですか？
Huh? Is that bad?
Of course it's bad!
当たり前だ！
桐皇(とうおう)との試合のとき…
At the Touou game,
you saw her honey-soaked lemons!
レモンはちみつ漬けとか見たろ！
つまり…
So...
料理の域は 完全に超えている
That's not cooking anymore.
You mean it's inedible?
（１年生たち）それ
食いもんじゃねぇってこと！？
Why don't we just cook for ourselves?
（福田(ふくだ)）じゃあ
自分らが作ればいいんじゃ？
I wish we could, but...
（日向）
そうしたいのはヤマヤマなんだが…
（伊月(いづき)）
練習メニューが殺人的すぎて—
Practice is so brutal,
no one can move at night.
夜は 誰も まともに動けん！
ヤベ 思い出したら…
Just thinking about it...
コガ〜！
Koga!
（１年生たち）
ああ〜 死ぬかもしんない…！
We might die!
Training Camp Menu Tasting
A tasting?
（降旗）試食会… ですか？
Training Camp Menu Tasting
We can't just tell her to practice because she sucks.
“マズいから練習しろ”なんて
言えねーだろ
By the way, can you guys cook?
（河原(かわはら)）ちなみに
先輩たち 料理 できるんですか？
A little.
だいたい なんでもー
Pretty much anything.
できん！
Nope!
Mitobe's probably the best. What about you, Kuroko?
一番は たぶん 水戸部(みとべ)かな？
黒子は？
No one makes a meaner boiled egg than me.
（黒子）ゆで卵なら負けません
It's ready!
はい できたわよ！ カレー！
Curry!
（一同）あれー！？
Curry?!
（伊月）いや… まるごと！？
Those are whole vegetables!
（小金井）さっきのトントントンは
なんだったの！？ トントントンは
What was that tapping sound?
What was that?
Just ignore what it looks like. It should taste fine!
まぁ 見た目は ともかく
味は大丈夫よ！ ただのカレーだし
It's just curry!
O-Okay, then...
じゃ… じゃあ
Thanks for the food.
（一同）いただきまーす
It's so bad!
（一同）マズーイ！
The rice is soft like porridge!
（土田）
おカユのように柔らかい米！
These crisp uncooked vegetables are like a salad!
（小金井）
サラダのようにシャキシャキと—
火の通ってない野菜たち！
And the meat is raw!
ていうか 生肉！
And the sauce is mysteriously bitter and sour!
（伊月）
そして ルーには 謎の苦みと酸味！
This is a massacre of flavor!
（日向）味の大虐殺やぁぁ！
Training Camp Menu Tasting
Let me know if you want more.
おかわり ジャンジャン言ってね
Training Camp Menu Tasting
She made a whole pot of it!
（一同）しかも 寸胴(ずんどう)ー！
It wasn't very good, was it?
（リコ）やっぱり あんまし
おいしくない… かな…
（日向）ごちそさん
Thanks for the food.
It tasted good, but it was a little spicy.
うまかったけど ちょっと
辛かったから 飲み物 買ってくるわ
I'm going to get something to drink.
Training Camp Menu Tasting
（木吉）
味は個性的だけど いけるよ
It had a unique flavor, but it was pretty good.
Training Camp Menu Tasting
It had the most important ingredient.
料理に 一番 大事なもんは
入ってる… 愛情がな
Love.
But you may have gone wrong somewhere with your cooking.
けど もしかしたら
どっかで作り方 間違ってるかもな
Why don't you try making it again?
もう１回
作ってみないか？
Okay.
Training Camp Menu Tasting
What men! You guys are such men!
（一同）オトコマエ！
オトコマエだよ アンタらは！
Training Camp Menu Tasting
Hyuga?
日向… 日向ァー！
Hyuga!
誰か
リコに 作り方 教えられねーか？
Can anyone teach Riko how to make it?
Kiyoshi, you're dripping some kind of weird sweat!
ていうか 木吉
変な汗 超出てる！
Mitobe, then...
（小金井）だったら 水戸… うわっ
（土田）水戸…
Mitobe?
（小金井）うわあっ！
召されちゃってますけど！？
He's gone!
So, who's going to teach her? Me or Izuki?
じゃあ 誰が教える？
オレか 伊月…
Here.
（火神）うっす！
What? This looks delicious!
えええ！？
なんか すげぇ うまそう！
Give me a taste!
ちょ… 一口 くれ！
It's so good!
うめぇぇ！
Kagami, how?
火神 なんで！？
I live by myself.
いや… オレ 一人暮らしだし…
（日向たち）
うまっ！ ほんとだ うまいな
This is so good.
What is this?
Kagami!
（リコ）火神君！
（火神）ん？
Teach me how to make curry!
カレーの作り方を… 教えて！
Sure, but I'm a strict teacher!
いっスけど…
オレは厳しいっスよ！
Wow! It looks so good!
いい！ いいよ うまそう！
It's curry! It's perfect!
カレーだよ！ カンペキ！
I got it this time! Dig in!
今度はバッチリよ！ さ どーぞ！
Thanks for the food!
（一同）いただきまーす！
You're kidding! Why?
ウソ！？ なんで！？
We don't know either.
（小金井）オレらにも分からん…
（土田）なんだ これは…？
What is this?
（伊月）ただ一つ言えることは…
The only thing I can say is...
It's as disgusting as ever!
Training Camp Menu Tasting
（一同）依然 マズイ！
Kagami, didn't you make it with her?
火神
一緒に作ったんじゃないの！？
I did. I even tasted it.
そっスよ！ 味見も したし
Then why?
じゃ なんで！？
Training Camp Menu Tasting
The coach's inability to cook is beyond human understanding.
（河原）カントクの料理の下手さは
人智(じんち)を超えてる…
But it's so bad it's almost amazing.
（小金井）逆に すごいな なんか
It's good.
おいしいですよ
黒子 もういい ムチャするな！
Kuroko, that's enough. Don't do anything crazy!
No, it really is good.
いえ 本当に…
No way...
（木吉）まさか！ 黒子 もしかして
自分で よそって食べたのか？
Training Camp Menu Tasting
Kuroko, did you serve yourself?
Yes. They forgot about me, so...
（黒子）はい 忘れられたので
Riko, could you plate another serving?
リコ
もう一度 よそってくれないか？
えっ？ いいけど…
Sure.
First, you put the rice on the plate.
まず ごはんでしょ
で ルーをかける前に…
Then, before you add the sauce...
Has she been putting cheese on there? That's some serious cooking.
（小金井）あ！ チーズ
かかってたんだ 凝ってんじゃ…
Hey! What is that?!
いや！？ 何？ それ
It's just protein and vitamin C powder.
（リコ）何って… プロテインとか
ビタミンＣの粉末とか
T-That's it!
（一同）そ… それだー！
It's normal!
（一同）普通だー！
Then say it tastes good!
（リコ）ちょ… そこは
おいしいって 言いなさいよー！
（伊月）磯の香りが… 急がねば！
I smell the beach. We must beach quickly!
Izuki, shut up.
（日向）伊月 黙れ
Let's swim!
（小金井）泳ごう！
This is a training camp, you idiot!
（日向）合宿だ！ ダアホ！
（テツヤ２号）わん！
Brats...
（景虎(かげとら)）ガキども
娘に手ぇ出したら… 殺すぞ
Lay a hand on my daughter,
and I'll kill you.
Yes, sir!
（一同）はいっ！
Thanks, Papa!
（リコ）ありがとう パパ
The coach's dad...
カントクの親父(おやじ)さん…
He's as scary as ever.
相変わらず こえー
So, what are those?
で あれは…
（リコ）ふふ〜ん
パパに頼んで 運んでもらったの
My dad brought them here for me.
（日向）なっ… まさか ここで？
Don't tell me we're going to...
Yup, we're going to play basketball.
（リコ）そう バスケするの
What?
チーム力の向上が
かけ算だとしても—
Imagine the team's power as an equation.
If the individual numbers are low, we'll never make a big number.
５人の数値が低ければ
大きな数値にはならない
今 誠凛(せいりん)に必要なもの それは
選手１人１人の個人能力の向上よ
What Seirin needs now
is to improve the skills of each individual player.
But don't get the wrong idea.
けど カン違いしないでね
We're not creating a team of individual strengths,
個人技を主体にした
チームにするわけじゃなく—
but increasing each one of the powers we combine as a team.
あくまで 束ねる力
一つ一つを大きくすることよ
Seirin wins as a team.
誠凛というチーム一丸で勝つために
Shooting, passing, dribbling...
シュート パス ドリブル…
In order to improve all of your actions,
一つ一つの
アクションの質を向上させる
we have to start with your legs and hips as the foundation.
それには まず 土台となる足腰よ
That's why we're practicing on the beach.
そのための砂浜練習
This is going to make us twice as tired.
これ 普通の 倍 疲れるぞ
We'll start by doing three times the normal amount of practice.
まずは ここで
いつものメニュー… の３倍よ
Let's get this training camp from hell started!
さぁ 始めるわよ 地獄の合宿！
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（火神）
全然 思うように動けねー！
I can't move at all!
Over here!
（日向）こっちだ！
Kuroko, you can't bounce your passes!
バウンドでパスして
どーすんだ 黒子ォ！
Since we can't dribble, we have to make plays by passing.
（伊月）ドリブルできないから
パスで組み立てるしかないのか
よし！ おぉぉぉ！
おぉっ！？ ぶほっ
Is dunking the only thing you can do, you moron?
オマエの辞書には マジ
ダンクしかないんか ダアホ！
Damn it.
くっそ…
Are you okay?
大丈夫？
Yeah, I'm fine.
あぁ 大丈夫だ
This will be perfect for whipping my body back into shape.
なまった体 たたき直すには
こんぐらいで ちょうどいい
Good work!
（リコ）お疲れ！
夕方からは 体育館に移動よ！
We'll move to the gym in the evening!
（一同）は… はい！
Okay.
I can get a way better grip than I usually do.
（日向）いつもより ずっと
いいカンジで指がかかる…！
Huh? It feels different than usual.
（伊月）え？ なんか前と違う 楽…
足か？ バタつかないっていうか
Is it easier?
Is it my legs? They aren't flopping around.
Everyone's movements have improved.
（木吉）
みんな 動きがよくなってる
We've started focusing more of our strength into the base of our big toes,
人間が地面を蹴るときに
一番 重要な 親指の付け根に—
the most important part of stepping on the ground.
力が集約されるようになったからだ
This must have been the real reason we practiced on the beach.
砂浜練習の本当の目的は これか…
You should have gone for a dunk there.
今のは ダンク行けよ フツーに
Was the timing off?
タイミング合わなかったのか？
If anything, wasn't it perfect?
（日向）むしろ
ピッタリだったんじゃねぇのか？
Did he hold back so he wouldn't jump too high?
跳びすぎを ためらった！？
Breaking       Waves        Guesthouse
Ow, ow!
いてっ！ いててっ！
強(つえ)えよ バカ！ オイ！
You're doing it too strong, you idiot!
あ すみません…
Sorry.
Are you thinking about something?
考えごとか？
新しいスタイルのことかよ？
Is it about your new style?
I'm a little concerned.
少し… 焦っています
まだ 手がかりひとつ掴めてません
I don't have any ideas yet.
I feel rejuvenated.
あー 生き返るー
Massage
You sound like an old man.
おっさん くさっ
Massage
Riko, have you seen Hyuga?
おー リコー
日向 見なかったかー？
He just went outside with a ball.
（リコ）
さっき ボール持って 表 出てった
（木吉）本当か？ かなわんなー
あいつの そういうトコ
Really? He's unbelievable like that.
Seirin High
Bath
What do you think of this training camp?
この合宿 どう思う？
What do I think?
どうって…
なんか 不満でもあるのか？
Is there something you're not satisfied with?
No, but...
そうじゃないけど…
You're doing the right thing.
リコの やってることは 正しいよ
This practice will improve everyone's fundamentals.
今の練習で
全員の基本スペックは確実に上がる
If there's a problem, it'll be with the players.
問題があるとしたら
オレら選手のほうだろうな
If there's anything that the team still needs to work on,
もし より
チームのレベルを上げるために—
必要なものがあるとすれば—
it's for each player to understand his role.
それは 選手１人１人が
自分の役割を知ること
You could call it establishing a style.
スタイルの確立と
言ってもいい
In order to learn a new technique,
仮に 何か
新技を身につけようとしても—
you have to understand yourself first.
それは 自分のことを知ってからだ
But Kuroko and the other second years haven't managed that yet.
だが 黒子は もちろん
２年生も まだ それが不完全だ
I hate how you act like you know everything.
何でも知ってるふうが…
ムカつく
What?
Seriously, why didn't you become the captain?
本当に どうして
キャプテンやらなかったの？
I don't have any complaints about Hyuga, but you're suited to the job too.
日向君に文句はないけど
鉄平(てっぺい)も向いてるわ やっぱり
Hyuga's a better fit.
日向のほうが適任だからだよ
You push them, and Hyuga pulls them.
リコが押して日向がひっぱる
それが いい
That's the best way.
It's why I asked him to do it.
だから オレは あいつに頼んだ
とにかく
今のままじゃ ダメってことね？
Anyway, you're saying we can't keep going at this rate, right?
If only we had some kind of spark.
何か きっかけでもあるとなー
A spark...
（リコ）きっかけ…
つぅ… 体 いって…
My body hurts so much.
うおお！ 毎度 わざとか テメェ！
Do you do that on purpose?
Good morning.
おはようございます
And your hair!
あと 寝グセ！
This place is a dump.
（高尾(たかお)）しっかし ボロいね〜
ホントに ここに泊まるのかよ？
Are we really staying here?
I feel like I'm going to see a ghost.
（高尾）なんか 出そうな感じ
Shut up, Takao.
（緑間(みどりま)）うるさいのだよ 高尾
て アレ？
Huh?
Hello. It's good to see you again.
どうも お久しぶりです
What are you doing here?
（緑間）
なぜ ここに いるのだよっ！？
I could ask you the same thing!
そりゃ こっちのセリフだよ！
（高尾）秀徳(しゅうとく)は昔から—
Shutoku has a long tradition of coming here to train together.
ここで 一軍の調整合宿するのが
伝統なんだと
And here you are enjoying your vacation!
それが オマエらはバカンスとは
いい身分なのだよ！
What's with the tan?
その日焼けは なんだ！
We're not on vacation!
（火神）バカンスじゃねーよ！
What?!
（緑間）えっ？
（リコ）ちょっと！
Hey!
We're all waiting for you in the cafeteria.
もう みんな
食堂で待ってるんですけど
What is your school, Kuroko?!
（緑間）オマエの学校は
なんなのだよ 黒子！
（黒子）誠凛高校です
It's Seirin High School.
That's not what I meant!
（緑間）
そういうことではないのだよ
Huh? Shutoku?
（リコ）あれっ！？ 秀徳さん！？
Welcome
Seirin
High School
Shutoku
Starting today, instead of holding our scheduled practice in the gym,
（リコ）今日から
体育館練習は予定変更で—
we're going to be practicing with Shutoku High!
秀徳高校と合同練習よ！
Kagami, hold on.
あ〜 火神君は ちょい待ち！
Go buy drinks for everyone.
みんなの分の 飲み物 買ってきて
What?
Run on the beach to the convenience store 500 meters away!
砂浜 走って 500メートル先の
コンビニまで ゴー！
Why?
（火神）なんで！？
They'll probably be heavy, so you can bring them one at a time.
重いだろうから
１本ずつで いいわよ
One at a time?
１本ずつ？
Everyone's practicing, so hurry!
（リコ）みんな練習してるんだから
早くね！
Hey, how many laps is that?!
それ
何往復させるんスか？
It really is amazing.
改めてみるとすごいな
１人１人の動きのレベルが違う
Everyone's movements have improved.
Is he trying to go one-on-one?
（高尾）あいつ
ワンオンワンとか したっけ？
（秀徳部員たち）よし！
That was a ridiculous attempt at a play.
ふざけたプレーを
するようになったな
It wasn't ridiculous.
ふざけてません ただ ボク自身が
もっと強くなりたいんです
I just want to get stronger.
（緑間）笑わせるな
Don't make me laugh.
青峰(あおみね)に負けて
何を思ったか知らんが—
I don't know what you felt after losing to Aomine,
but we already know your limits.
黒子 オマエの力など
たかが知れているのだよ
I thought you played knowing them.
それを自覚した
バスケをしていたはずだが…
それでも もっと頑張れば
なんとかなると思ったか？
Did you really think something would happen if you tried harder?
A man who cannot play by himself cannot improve by himself.
１人で戦えない男が
１人で強くなろうなどできるものか
Kagami's running outside.
（大坪(おおつぼ)）火神は
外に走りに出ているようです
Are they hiding something?
何か隠しているんでしょうか？
No.
（中谷(なかたに)）違うな 火神の武器は
跳ぶ度に高さが増すジャンプ力だ
Kagami's strength is his jumps that increase in height with every one he does.
Even during a game.
しかも 試合中に
They're powered not by spirit or will, but something physical.
あれは 気合いや根性といった
精神論ではなく—
ちゃんとタネがある
それに気付いての仕込みだろう
She must have realized what it is and is now training it.
She's an impressive coach.
大した監督だよ それに…
On top of that...
Kiyoshi Teppei...
木吉鉄平
恐ろしいヤツが戻ってきたな
A formidable opponent has returned.
だっはー 生き返るわー
I feel rejuvenated.
つーか いつまで ふくれてんだよ
How long are you going to sulk for anyway?
It's starting to get annoying.
さすがに そろそろ ウゼーから
Kuroko's regular play is nothing special.
しかし 黒子
普通のプレーは からっきしだなー
He's got his unfair misdirection though.
ミスディレクションなんて
反則技 持ってんのに…
つーか
ミスディレクション—
He should use his misdirection when he breaks away.
抜くとき
使えばいーじゃん
An invisible dribble would be unstoppable.
見えないドリブルとか
無敵じゃね？
It's impossible.
それは無理なのだよ
Do you know why Kuroko only makes tap passes?
黒子が なぜ
タップパスしかしないか分かるか？
Because he cannot direct attention away from the ball.
（緑間）ボールから 意識を
そらすことができないからだ
During a game, you must never take your eyes off the ball.
試合中 最も 目を
離してはならないものはボールだ
In other words, it has more presence than anything else on the court.
つまり コートで
最も存在感のある物体なのだよ
That is why Kuroko never holds the ball.
だから
黒子は ボールを決して持たない
Unable to use his misdirection while holding the ball,
もし持てば ミスディレクションが
発動できず—
Seirin.....................................................Shutoku
たちまち
ボールを奪われてしまうだろう
Seirin.....................................................Shutoku
it will not be long before someone steals it from him.
だが 逆に… その弱点を
克服する方法があるとしたら…
However, conversely,
if there were a way to overcome this weakness,
he'd probably show terrifying improvement.
恐ろしい進化を遂げるかもしれん
That's great, but...
（高尾）それは いいけど—
you've been talking to a lion for a while now.
さっきから しゃべってる相手
それライオン
あー サッパリした
I feel refreshed.
（火神）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
ギャー！
I just finished shopping.
（火神）今
買い終わったんだよ！ あ… です
What? Just now?
え？ 今まで！？
No one was in the gym when I got back.
（火神）体育館 戻ったら
誰もいねーし…
I'm sure these weren't meant for drinking, but here.
どーせ 飲むためじゃ
ねーだろーけど… はい
（リコ）ちょ… これ まさか…—
Did you buy drinks for Shutoku as well as us?
ウチだけじゃなくて
秀徳の人たちの分も！？
How many laps did you run?
一体 何往復してきたのよ？
（火神）あー 疲れた〜 風呂 風呂
I'm so tired.
Time for a bath.
（リコ）言われた量を
こなすどころか 完全に超えてる！
He did way more than I asked him to do!
We won't see the results for a while,
成果が出るのは まだ先…
but if he keeps training like this, he'll become an unbelievable player!
でも このまま鍛え続ければ
彼は とんでもない選手になる！
ダァッ…
What?
The bath's already closed?
（火神）
風呂 もう終わりかよ！ ですか？
Is it?
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
（黒子）おはようございます
Good morning.
（高尾）おはよう… ブフッ
Morning...
ひでえな その頭
Your hair is ridiculous!
It seems to get messed up easily in my sleep.
（黒子）
寝グセ つきやすいみたいで
（高尾）それにしても ねえよ
That's still way too much.
あっ オマエも 真(しん)ちゃんみたいに
かぶれば いいんじゃね？
Why don't you wear a night cap like Shin?
Episode 22
I'll Win Even if it Kills Me
ナイトキャップ
No.
（黒子）遠慮します